(銀時/新八)まだまだだね…｡
そのおこぼれじゃねえ？ って
言ってたね｡
いや そうじゃなくて
実はですね なんか 最近➡
(神楽)本当ね｡ 尺を埋めるﾈﾀも
もう尽きたあるか？
つうか １年前も
同じこと やってなかった？
(銀時/新八)えっ…？
(神楽)
すごい褒めてたある ｢ﾃﾆﾌﾟﾘ｣を｡
ようやく このｱﾆﾒにも 春が…｡
(神楽)あぁ その話！
(銀時)おいおい！
なんで 今さら このｱﾊﾞﾝ？
ﾃﾚﾋﾞ東京での視聴率が
結構いいみたいで これを機に➡
おぉ～！ ｺﾞｰﾙﾃﾞﾝから左遷されて
苦節 １年半…｡
(新八)侍の国 ﾎﾞｸらの国が
そう呼ばれていたのは…｡
この前 ﾃﾚ東の人が ４月から
『銀魂』の前に始まった➡
『ﾃﾆｽの王子様』の再放送が
すっごい好調だから➡
新規で観始めた方にも 『銀魂』の
世界観を説明できればいいなって｡
["Previously on GinTama"]
"Land of the Samurai." The days when our
country was called that are long past.
What's with the intro? Didn't we
already do that a year ago?
Have we run out of new material?
No, actually, TV-Tokyo's ratings
have been pretty good,
so we thought it'd be nice to explain the
GinTama world to our new viewers.
So after a year and a half of hard time,
spring has finally come to this anime!
I heard it was because reruns of "The
Prince of Tennis" that started in April,
in the time slot before GinTama,
are doing extremely well.
Eh?
He was lavish in his praise
for "The Prince of Tennis."
We've got ways to go...
[Note: Parody of "You've got ways to go" famous
phrase by Ryoma Echizen from Prince of Tennis.]
[Thanks to capitalizing on another show's popularity,
"GinTama" continues its successful run!]
[So in response to the good fortune of a certain
sports series... This week we try soccer.]
(歓声)
≪(中野)さぁ 時間は 後半 ﾛｽﾀｲﾑ｡
Here we go! We're in stoppage time
in the second half!
≪ここにきて
ＦＣ大江戸 最後のﾁｬﾝｽだ！
This is FC Oedo's last chance to score!
(長谷川)頼んだぜ｡
(桂)いけ｡
Come on...
Go.
Do it!
(近藤)決めろ！
(お妙)任せたわよ！
It's up to you!
(さっちゃん)今よ！
(神楽)打つある！
Now!
Kick it!
そこだ！
(おじいさん)ﾌｶﾞ～！
This is it!
(歓声)
Kick it in, Amarao!
叩き込め 甘羅尾！
(甘羅尾)うぉ～っ!!
[Two hours and 40 minutes earlier...]
Strikers are beasts that
live to score goals.
《甘羅尾:ｽﾄﾗｲｶｰ… それは
ｺﾞｰﾙという獲物を追い続ける獣｡
What waits at the end of the road
for those who seek to score?
その獲物を追い求めてきた
旅路の先で➡
待っているものは なんだろう？
この旅の終着点となる
今日の試合でも➡
If I remain true to what I believe,
even in this match that marks the end
of the road...I will see everything.
自分の信念を貫ければ
すべてが見えてくるはずだ｡
[Locker Room]
このｵﾚの ｺﾞｰﾙを追い続けた
人生の先にある新たな世界が…》
The new world...
that awaits me after a
life of scoring goals!
Okay!
(甘羅尾)よし いくぞ!! お前ら！
Here we go, team!
(甘羅尾)えっ…？
Huh?
(うめき声)
(甘羅尾)えっ…？
(甘羅尾)えぇ～っ!?
What?!
["Love Is Often Played Out In Sudden Death"]
[Oedo Stadium]
(救急車のｻｲﾚﾝ)
Hey!
お～い!!
What is this?! What's going on?!
何!? これ！
いったい これ どうなってるの？
Who are you? Who are you people?!
つうか 誰!?
ｱﾝﾀら いったい 誰!?
Wh-Who are we, you ask?
だ… 誰って言われても… なぁ？
Well, we're like beer vendors.
まぁ ﾋﾞｰﾙの売り子的な… ねぇ？
We came here to sell beer,
ﾋﾞｰﾙ 売りにきたら ｺｲﾂら➡
試合前に ﾋﾞｰﾙは飲めない ﾎﾞｶﾘしか
飲みたくない って言ったある｡
but they said they couldn't
drink beer before a match.
They said they only wanted Bocari,
[Note: Bocari is a wordplay on Pocari Sweat,
a Japanese sports drink, available in powder form.]
so I went looking for Bocari powder
and made some for them.
だから 私 わざわざ
ﾎﾞｶﾘの粉 探して 作ってやったね｡
No! That wasn't Bocari powder!
(甘羅尾)違うよ それ！
ﾎﾞｶﾘの粉じゃないから!!
That was the powder they
use to mark the field lines!
ﾃﾞｯﾄﾞ ｵｱ ｱﾗｲﾌﾞの境界線の粉だから！
もう 試合 始まるんだぞ！ つうか
なんてこと してくれたんだよ!!
The game's about to start!
What have you people done?!
What am I going to do now?!
いったい どうすりゃいいんだよ!?
ｵﾚは！
新八… 誰だ？ ｺｲﾂ｡
Shinpachi, who is this guy?
あれですよ ＦＣ大江戸のｽﾀｰ選手
甘羅尾 大作ですよ｡
He's, you know, FC Oedo's star
player, Daisaku Amarao.
Amarao-san, you don't have
to make such a big deal of it.
あの～ 甘羅尾さんよ そんな
大騒ぎしなくていいじゃない｡
It didn't bother me one bit that I waited until
August 31 to do my summer homework.
[Note: In Japan, August 31st is the last day of
summer vacation for elementary school kids.]
ｵﾚなんか あれだよ ８月31日まで
夏休みの宿題 やってなくても➡
全然 動じなかったよ｡
今日は…
ｵﾚの引退試合だったんだ｡
Today was...my final
game before I retire.
引退試合？
Your retirement game?
Yes...and I'm the symbol of
this team. Its best player.
(甘羅尾)あぁ
自分で言うのも なんだが➡
ｵﾚは このﾁｰﾑのｼﾝﾎﾞﾙ的存在だ｡
今まで20年間 ＦＣ大江戸ひと筋に
数々のｺﾞｰﾙを奪ってきた｡
For the past 20 years, I've remained with
FC Oedo and scored countless goals.
そして それ以上のｺﾞｰﾙを
夜の街で量産し ｻﾎﾟｰﾀｰからは➡
And above all, I'm an ace
striker who has made
a massive amount of scores every night.
夜の得点王 合ｺﾝの司令塔と
親しまれてきた ｴｰｽｽﾄﾗｲｶｰだ｡
My fans call me the "night-on-the-town's ace"
and the "command tower of group dates".
No, I think they're looking down on
you. What kind of ace is that?
いや 見下されてるだろ それ｡
何のｴｰｽだよ？
(甘羅尾)全盛期には 数々の
伝説となるｺﾞｰﾙを築いた ｵﾚは➡
During my prime, I scored countless
legendary goals. I'm a fantasista.
[Note: Fantasista is an Italian term
for a superstar soccer player.]
そう… ﾌｧﾝﾀｼﾞｽﾀ｡
Are you a fool or something?
What're you fantasizing about?
おい！ ﾊﾞｶだろ!? お前｡
どんなﾌｧﾝﾀｼﾞｰだよ！
そんなｵﾚの引退試合が
不戦敗だなんて➡
I can't lose my retirement
game by forfeit.
I'll disappoint my fans.
ﾌｧﾝを悲しませるだけだ｡
いや… ｱﾝﾀの経歴が すでに
不戦敗な気がするんですけど｡
No, I think you've already
forfeited your life history.
I realize that...
わかってるさ…｡
でも 今日だけは違う！
But today is different!
Today...I wanted to make my precious
little boy's wish come true!
今日だけは… この引退試合で➡
ｵﾚの大事な息子の願いを
叶えてやりたいと思ってたんだ！
じゃあ 息子さんのために
今日 ｺﾞｰﾙを…？
You wanted to score a goal
today for your little boy?
そうだよ！
そのつもりだったんだよ！
That's right! That's what
I planned on doing.
それを こんなにしやがって…
わかったよ!! もう 死のう！
But look what you've done!
Forget it, I'll just die!
ｵﾚが死にゃあいいんだ！
今すぐ死のう！
I should just die right now! Sis, hand
over some of that Bocari! A big cup!
ねえちゃん ｵﾚにもﾎﾞｶﾘ大盛りで！
はいｱﾙ｡
Coming right up.
な～っ！ 待て 待て！ ちょっ…｡
W-Wait! Wait! Just a minute!
There's no need to die!
なにも 死ぬこと
ないじゃないですか！
じゃあ ｱﾝﾀら どうしてくれんだ!?
責任 取ってくれんの？
Then what're you people
going to do about it?
Are you to going to take
responsibility for this?!
人を集めるでも 何でもいいよ！
Gather up some people, do something!
とにかく 試合ができるよう
なんとかしてくれよ！
Just set things up so we
can play the game!
そうじゃないと…
息子が… ｵﾚの息子が…｡
If you don't...my little boy will...he'll...
ﾊｧ… わかった わかったよ｡
All right, all right. I'll take care
of this. Give me some time.
とりあえず ｵﾚが何とかすっから
ちょっと待っててくれ｡
ﾎﾝﾄｫ～!?
ﾊｧ…｡
Really?!
待たせたな｡
Thanks for waiting.
急な話で あれだったが➡
It was rather sudden, but I think
I rounded you up quite a group.
自分でも なかなかのﾒﾝﾂを
揃えられたと思うぜ｡
見ろ！ これが
新生ＦＣ大江戸のﾒﾝﾊﾞｰだ！
Look! These are the new
FC Oedo team members!
ｼﾞｰｻﾞｽ ｸﾗｲｽﾄ～ｯ！ …って
何なんだよ この連中は!?
Jesus Christ!
What is this?! Who are these people?!
どこの仮装大会ですか？ これは！
もう 欽ちゃんいないと➡
What costume party did you find them
at?! All that's missing is Kin-chan!
[Note: Refers to Kinichi Hagimoto who
used to host a costume contest.]
不自然なﾚﾍﾞﾙじゃねえか！
どこだよ 欽ちゃん どこ～っ!?
Where is he? Where's Kin-chan?!
(神楽)晋也も必要ｱﾙ｡
We need Shinya, too.
[Note: Shinya Yamomoto is a judge in the
Kinichi Hagimoto's costume contest.]
どこだよ!? 監督 どこ～っ！
…って ﾊﾞｶ！
Where is he? Where's the director?!
This is ridiculous!
[Note: Director is Shinya Yamamoto's nickname.]
何を慌てている｡
我々が来たからには➡
What're you so flustered about?
[Note: Katsura is wearing a Nankatsu team uniform that says "Tonkatsu" (Pork cutlet). Elizabeth is dressed as Kojiro Hyuga from Captain Tsubasa]
Now that we're here, there's no problem.
もう何も問題ない｡ 見てのとおり
ｻｯｶｰの知識に関しては➡
As you can see, we've studied up
perfectly on the game of soccer.
完璧に予習してある｡
[I'm Morisaki.]
[Note: Refers to Yuzo Morisaki from Nankatsu FC.]
(甘羅尾)うっせ～よ!!
隣のﾔﾂ 早速 間違ってるよ！
Quiet! The one next to you
is wrong from the get-go!
(甘羅尾)つか ｵﾒｴら ｢ｷｬﾌﾟつば｣
読んできただけだろ！
You probably just read Captain Tsubasa.
[Note: Captain Tsubasa is a soccer manga.]
｢ｷｬﾌﾟつば｣じゃない｡
ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝ ｶﾂｰﾗだ｡
I'm not Captain Tsubasa.
I'm Captain Katsura.
(甘羅尾)知るか！
Who cares!
Excuse me, what're we doing?
(さっちゃん)
ねぇ ちょっと… なぁに？
(さっちゃん)久しぶりの出番かと
思いきや 手を使わないで➡
It's been a long time since
I made an appearance.
I was asked to come to a contest where you
roll balls around without using your hands...
玉を転がす競技をするから
来いなんて… 随分 ﾏﾆｱｯｸね｡
How freaky.
上等じゃない!! 銀さん
早く あなたの玉を出しな…｡
That's fine with me! Gin-san,
take out your balls.
ﾀｲｶﾞｰｯ!!
ｼｮｰｯ！
Tiger!
[Note: Tiger shot is a special move of
Kojiro Hyuga from Captain Tsubara.]
え～っ？ 私は
蹴りまくるｽﾎﾟｰﾂって聞いたから➡
What?
I heard we were doing a sport
that involved a lot of kicking,
こんな格好で来たのに…｡
so I came dressed like this.
[Note: Otae is wearing a Thai kickboxing outfit.]
えっ？ ｵﾚは 玉を自由自在に
操るところを みんなに➡
What?!
I heard it was a sport where everyone
watches all the cool things
you can do with your balls,
so I came like this.
見られる競技って聞いたから
こんな格好で来たのにさぁ｡
え～っ？ ｵﾚは いちばん独創的な
いなり寿司を作ったﾔﾂが➡
What?! I heard the person who makes the
most unique Inari zushi was the winner,
[Note: Inari zushi is a tofu pouch packed
with rice. Looks like nuts.]
優勝だと聞いて
こんな格好で来たのに…｡
so I came like this.
おい!! 最後のﾔﾂにいたっては➡
Hey! Every one of you guys
thinks this is about nads!
もう 金玉の話しか
してねえじゃねえか！
もう試合 始まっちゃうよ…｡
こんなﾒﾝﾊﾞｰで どうやって➡
The game's about the start!
How're we going to play
soccer with this group?!
どうやって ｻｯｶｰすんだよ！
ねぇ 銀さん｡
Gin-san, all of us together make
only ten. We're short one.
ここにいる 全員 合わせても
10人しかいませんよ｡
１人 足りませんよ｡
え～っ そうなの？
Huh? Is that so?
(甘羅尾)｢え～っ そうなの？｣
じゃねえよ！
Don't just say "Is that so?" Soccer
is played with 11 people!
ｻｯｶｰは 11人でやるｽﾎﾟｰﾂなの！
おい もう ﾎﾝﾄ やばいよ｡
時間ないよ！
We're really in trouble
now! There's no time!
(甘羅尾)どうしてくれんだよ！
どうするつもりだよ!!
What're you going to do?! Come on!
There, we have everyone.
ほら これで全員 揃った｡
ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬ 間に合わせじゃねえか！
つうか このじいさん 大丈夫!?
You just slapped this team together!
You sure this old geezer is any good?
ｳｩｯ…｡
やる気満々かよ!?
Well at least he's not deaf.
ちょっ… ちょっと
何なんですか!? 甘羅尾さん！
Wait a minute, what's going
on, Amarao-san?
Huh?
この相手ﾁｰﾑ…｡
The opposing team...
なんか 全員
同じ顔してるんですけど…｡
They all have the same face.
(甘羅尾)あぁ 11つ子だからな｡
え～っ!?
They were 11 kids born
at the same time.
What?!
(甘羅尾)
今日の相手ﾁｰﾑは大江戸ｱﾝﾋﾞﾊﾞﾚﾝﾂ｡
Today's opponent is the
Oedo Ambivalence.
(甘羅尾)ﾚｷﾞｭﾗｰ全員が 11つ子の
松野兄弟で占められている｡
All positions are played by
the 11 Matsuno brothers.
おかあさんの顔
見てみたいです…｡
I'd like to see their mother.
(ｻﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)甘羅尾！
今日は決めろよ！
Amarao! Make sure you score today!
[Go, Go Amarao!]
いけ～っ！ 夜の得点王！
(笑い声)
Go! You're the night-on-the-town's
top scorer, right?
(ｻﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)期待してんぞ！ 甘羅尾！
We're counting on you, Amarao!
(ｻﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)最後くらい
ｻｯｶｰで かっこつけろよ！
At least look good in your last game!
《終わったな…
こんな素人たちとじゃ➡
I'm finished.
There's no way we can play a decent
game with these amateurs.
まともな試合
できるわけがねえ…》
(少年)がんばれ！ 甘羅尾！
Go for it! Amarao!
《あっ… もしかして あの子が
さっき言ってた息子さん…？》
Could that be the little boy
he talked about earlier?
《そうだ… 諦めちゃいけねえ｡
どんな素人でも➡
That's right...I mustn't give up.
No matter how inexperienced they are, with
proper directions, we might pull it off.
ｵﾚが的確に指示を出せば
なんとかなるかもしれん…》
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
≪さぁ 試合開始です｡
The game is about to begin.
本日の実況は 私
中野が お送りいたします｡
I'm Nakano, and I'll be your
announcer for today.
≪ﾎﾞｰﾙは 大江戸ｱﾝﾋﾞﾊﾞﾚﾝﾂでｽﾀｰﾄ｡
The Oedo Ambivalence starts things off.
≪松野 三男 ﾄﾞﾘﾌﾞﾙで
相手陣に切り込みます！
Sannan Matsuno dribbles and
slashes into the defense.
ﾃﾞｨﾌｪﾝﾀﾞｰ！ ﾏﾝﾂｰﾏﾝで 確実に
ﾏｰｸしろ！ 自由にさせるな！
Defenders! Stay on your mark, man-to-man!
Don't let them move freely!
(近藤/さっちゃん)了解！
Gotcha!
I have my man!
ﾏｰｸ ｵｯｹｰ！
(近藤)ﾏｰｸ ｵｯｹｰ！
I have mine!
(甘羅尾)…って おい！
なに 味方ﾏｰｸしてんだ!?
Hey! You're guarding your
own teammates?!
うるせぇ！
恋のﾏｰｸは いつでも…｡
Shut up! When you go after
the one you love...
ﾏﾝﾂｰﾏﾝに決まってるでしょ！
You always go man-to-man!
お妙さ～ん!!
Otae-san!
I won't let you go!
離さないわよ！
Now Sannan Matsuno...
≪なんと！ ここで 松野 三男
ｺﾞｰﾙ前に鋭いｽﾙｰﾊﾟｽだ！
makes a sharp pass towards the
goal right through the defense!
ｸﾘｱ！ とにかく ｸﾘｱだ!!
Clear! Just clear it!
(お妙/銀時)ｸﾘｱ！
Clear!
新ちゃん やったわ！
玉を２つもｸﾘｱしちゃった｡
Shin-chan, I did it. I cleared two balls.
姉上！ 女の子が
玉２つとか言ったら ﾀﾞﾒだから!!
Sis! A girl shouldn't be
talking about two balls!
≪ﾎﾞｰﾙはそのまま ｺﾞｰﾙ前に走り込む
松野 十一男のもとへ！
The ball is grabbed by Juichinan Matsuno.
He races toward the goal.
(甘羅尾)くるぞ！ ｷｰﾊﾟｰ！
He's coming your way, goalkeeper!
Okay, I'll guard this side of the
line, and Elizabeth, you...
(桂)よし ここから こっちを
ｵﾚが担当するから ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽはだな…｡
あっ きったねえ！
そっち ｵﾚより広いじゃん！
That's not fair! That side's
bigger than mine.
何を言っている！
この境界線は絶対だ！
What're you talking about?
This boundary is absolute.
What do you mean by absolute?!
Hey! What're you setting territories for?!
(甘羅尾)って おい！
なに陣地決め やってんだよ！
I swear to God, they are absolute!
っていうか なんで ｷｰﾊﾟｰ３人!?
Why are there three goalkeepers?!
はい 空中ｾｰﾌ！
おい！ 空中もｱｳﾄ！
Okay, above the line's okay.
Above the line is still out of bounds! You're
gonna get penalized! Definitely penalized!
お前 罰な！ 絶対 罰な！
やってみろよ！
罰やってみろよ！
I dare you! I dare you to penalize me!
お前 死刑な！ 絶対 死刑な！
なにを～!?
You get the death penalty!
Definitely the death penalty!
What?!
お前 絶対 しっぺ５回だかんな！
You'll definitely get five whacks!
What'd you do that for?!
なにしやがるんだ！
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…｡
Elizabeth...
[We should all share this space...]
[We are...]
[...teammates!]
ｱﾝﾀ…！
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…｡
You...
Elizabeth...
(桂)よし やるぞ！
Okay, let's do this!
おう！ ｵﾚたちは仲間だ！
ｵﾚたちは仲間だ！
Right! We're teammates!
Teammates!
[That's right! That's right!]
Hey! Hey!
(２人)ｴｲ ｴｲ…！
≪ｺﾞｰﾙ！ 先制点は
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
ｱｳｪｲのｱﾝﾋﾞﾊﾞﾚﾝﾂだ！
Goal!
The visiting Ambivalence scores first!
だ… 大丈夫ですよ！
It's all right. We'll have
many more chances.
まだまだ ﾁｬﾝｽは
たくさんありますから！
いや そうもいかないんだ｡
え…？
No, we won't.
ここにいるﾔﾂだけでも
聞いておいてほしい｡
Only you people here should hear this.
ｵﾚの体は 長年の戦いのせいで
もう ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛなんだ｡
My body is a wreck from all my battles
on the field over the years.
この膝も そして腰も➡
These knees,
this back,
もう とっくに限界がきてる！
have all reached their
limits a long time ago.
この試合中に あと何回
全力で ｼｭｰﾄが打てるか➡
I don't know how many more times I can
shoot for the goal with all my might.
ｵﾚにもわからねえ… だから！
That's why...!
何度とは言わねえ！
一度… 一度だけでもいいから➡
I'm not asking for repeated chances!
One...just one shot is enough.
Give me one chance at a goal!
ｵﾚに ｺﾞｰﾙのﾁｬﾝｽを
作ってくれないか！
ふぅ そんなこと言われても
ｵﾚたちゃ 素人だぜ｡
You say that, but we're amateurs...
まっ やれることは
やってやるけどよ！
But we'll do what we can.
新ちゃん！ 神楽ちゃん！
(２人)はい…！
Shin-chan, Kagura-chan.
Right.
Okay.
みんな…！
...Everyone...
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
≪さあ ＦＣ大江戸ﾎﾞｰﾙで
試合再開です！
The game continues with FC Oedo
in possession of the ball.
頼むぜ！
おっと… とは言ってみたものの➡
I'm counting on you.
Oh... Having said that, we've
never played soccer before.
こちとら ｻｯｶｰなんて
やったことねえからなぁ！
≪おっと 坂田選手
ﾎﾞｰﾙを奪われた！
Sakata has it stolen away!
We don't have the guts!
[Note: Famous phrase from a Captain Tsubasa video
game. Displayed when Energy (guts) is low.]
ﾍﾍｯ ﾁｮﾛｲもんだぜ！
ｺｲﾂら 素人ばっかりじゃねえか！
This is going to be easy!
They're nothing but amateurs!
追加点いただき～！
I'll increase our lead!
≪打った～！
ﾎﾞｰﾙは一直線に ｺﾞｰﾙへ！
He shoots!
The ball is headed straight
towards the goal!
≪ｷｰﾊﾟｰは ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ選手１人～！
Elizabeth is their only goalkeeper!
≪どうやら さっきのｺﾞｰﾙ後に➡
After the last goal, it seems they decided who would
be the goalkeeper using rock-paper-scissors!
誰が ｷｰﾊﾟｰをやるか
ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝで決めていたようです！
≪飛んだ～！ だが体型が災いして
わずかに届かないか～！
The ball is in the air. But will Elizabeth's
physique get in the way?!
≪ｽｰﾊﾟｰｾｰﾌﾞ！
It's a spectacular save!
≪ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ選手 まさかのｽｰﾊﾟｰｾｰﾌﾞ！
Elizabeth makes a spectacular,
unexpected save!
≪というか もはや 何の生き物か
わからない様相を呈しています！
Makes you wonder what
sort of creature it is!
≪おっと！
前線の選手は もう敵陣深くに！
The front line has raced deep into
the opponent's side of the field.
Goalkeeper! This is our chance
to counterattack!
ｷｰﾊﾟｰ！ ｶｳﾝﾀｰﾁｬﾝｽだ！
ｺﾞｰﾙ前に 蹴り込め！
Kick it out in front of their goal!
The goalkeeper makes a nice feed!
≪おおっと ｷｰﾊﾟｰ！
これは ﾅｲｽﾌｨｰﾄﾞだ！
With this...
Amarao!
《これなら…➡
I can make his wish come true.
これなら 願いを叶えてやれる！
ぐわっ… ｸｿｯ！
こんなときに痛みが…！》
Damn! Why does this
have to happen now!
大丈夫ですか 甘羅尾さん！
Are you okay, Amarao-san?
Don't worry! It's a badge of
honor I got during a game!
心配するな 試合で負った
名誉の負傷だ!!
《そう… あのときも
今日みたいに 激戦だった》
Yes...it was during a hard-fought
game like today!
[Cabaret Chic Hostess Bar]
C'mon, Ohana-chan, why won't
you go out with me?
((ねぇねぇ お華ちゃ～ん！
いいかげん
ｵﾚと 付きあってくれよ～！
(華)え～ どうしよっかなぁ？
What should I do? I'll consider it if you do
the Amarao Dance you do at the game.
あ！ いつも試合でやってる
甘羅尾ﾀﾞﾝｽ！
見せてくれたら
考えてもいいよ！
え～ そんなんでいいの!?
Is that all? Okay, here goes.
Hora, hora, hora.
いくよ ほらほら～！
ｱﾊﾊﾊ!!
あっ ﾌﾙｰﾂ盛り１つ ｱﾊﾊ!!
One fruit plate, please.
Here comes the signature pose!
いくよ～ はい 決めﾎﾟｰｽﾞ！))
I never imagined that "game" would
force me into retirement.
まさか あの試合で➡
引退に追い込まれるとは
思っていなかったが…｡
A...ma...ra...o...!
(みんな)あ～ ま～ ら～ お～!!
え？
Huh?!
From start to finish...
それ 一から十まで…｡
全部お前の！
You totally got...
what you deserved!
自業自得の!!
せいだろうが～!!
It's your own stupid fault!
Shoot!
(みんな)ｼｭｰﾄ！
ぶべらっ！
今日… だけは…｡
...not today...
≪ここで 前半終了です｡
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
That concludes the first half.
うおりゃ～!!
とりゃ～！
うぅ…！
Hey! What're you doing?!
って おい～!!
何やってんだよ～！
What, Shinpachi-kun? Balls
always go with bats, right?
何 って新八君
球とくれば 次は 棒の出番だろ？
Shut up! Can't you people even remember what
sport you were playing just a second ago?!
うるせぇ!!
ｵﾒｴは さっきまで➡
何やってたのかも
思い出せねえのかよ!!
No. My memory went splat after
I got kicked in the balls.
いや～ 玉を蹴られた際に
記憶が曖昧になって…｡
Are your brains in your balls?!
ｵﾒｴの脳みそは 玉にあんのか!?
Gin-san! I want the bat between
your legs right now!
銀さん 早く 股のﾊﾞｯﾄを私に！
That's enough!
しつけぇんだよ!!
うがぁ～!!
You stop that, too!
あぁ もういいから
あなたも！
Sarutobi-san, a woman must never say such
vulgar things such as bats, poles, and bleep.
猿飛さん 女性が棒とか
ﾊﾞｯﾄとか さおとか➡
…とか言っちゃ はしたないわ｡
Hey! You're more vulgar than she is!
おい！ ｱﾝﾀが
もっとはしたないよ！
Why're all of you panicking?
何を慌てている？
お前たち｡
後半こそ このﾌｨｰﾙﾄﾞの貴公子
みす… う!!
In the second half, I, Misugi,
the prince of this field, shall?
[Note: Jun Misugi is a player with heart disease from Captain Tsubasa. Uniform says "Kakashi" a wordplay on his team "Musashi FC."]
む… 胸が…｡
来るな ﾏﾈｰｼﾞｬｰ!!
M-My heart. Stay back, manager!
I can still play.
[Misugi-kun!]
ﾎﾞｸは まだ やれる!!
うぜぇ～!!
I will get them all with an off-side
trap in the second half...
Cut that out! How long are you going
to keep playing Captain Tsubasa!
いつまで ｢ｷｬﾌﾟつば｣ごっこ
引っ張ってんだ～！
Gin-san, this is totally messed up. How'll
we manage in the second half?
銀さん… なんか
もう ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬですよ！
こんなんじゃ 後半…｡
知るかよ｡
How would I know?
ﾊﾞｶな遊びばっかり
やってきたﾔﾂなんだろ？ ｱｲﾂは｡
You're talking about the guy who did
nothing but stupid things out there.
Maybe we should do as we please, too.
ｵﾚらも 好き勝手やりゃあ
いいんじゃねえの？
But that's...
そんな！
Amarao-san...
あ… 甘羅尾さん！
≪さぁ 間もなく 後半開始です｡
The second half is about to start.
In the first half,
前半は ﾚｷﾞｭﾗｰを欠くなか
０対１と善戦した ＦＣ大江戸｡
FC Oedo managed to keep the score
at 0-1 despite missing their regulars.
後半 逆転できますでしょうか？
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
Can they catch up in the second half?
The ball goes to Amarao.
≪さぁ 甘羅尾にﾎﾞｰﾙがわたる！
甘羅尾さん！
Amarao-san!
《忘れていた…｡
I'd forgotten. I always did things myself.
ｵﾚは いつだって
１人で やってきたんだ！》
《自分のために 己１人の力で！》
For my own sake, using
my own strength!
Amarao races deep into the enemy's
side of the field all alone!
≪甘羅尾
１人で 敵陣深く切れ込んだ！
うお～!!
(松野)させるか～!!
No you don't!
ぐわぁ!!
≪あ～っと ｲｴﾛｰｶｰﾄﾞ!!
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
He draws a yellow card!
FC Oedo gets a penalty kick!
≪ＦＣ大江戸 ＰＫを得たぞ！
《…そう これで いいんだ》
Yes...
All Right! Go!
This is how it should be...
(神楽)うり～!!
え？
Huh?!
あ～ 何やってんの～!?
What're you doing?!
Huh?!
え？ うわ～!!
ほべらっ!!
Wh-Why do things...turn out this way?
[Note: Famous phrase by Kinichi Hagimoto,
from the costume contest.]
《な… なんで
こう… なるの…》
《どうしちまったんだ…》
What happened to...
あっ 試合は!?
The match!
…ｸｯ!!
≪ｱﾝﾋﾞﾊﾞﾚﾝﾂ 更に追加点！
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
Ambivalence adds another point!
(中野)おっ どうやら ここで
負傷退場していた➡
Looks like Amarao who was out with an
injury is coming back into the game.
甘羅尾が ﾋﾟｯﾁに戻るようです｡
Amarao-san...we're sorry.
甘羅尾さん… すみません｡
(甘羅尾)いや 悪かったな｡
ここまで 付きあわせちまって｡
No, I'm to blame for getting
you involved in this.
時間は
もう ﾛｽﾀｲﾑしか残ってねえ｡
All we have left is stoppage time.
確かに ｵﾚは ｻｯｶｰ人生
ﾊﾞｶばっかやってきた｡
It's true that I did nothing but stupid
things during my soccer career.
そのﾂｹが
今日 回ってきたのかもな｡
That came back to haunt me today.
だが 最後までｺﾞｰﾙは諦めねえ｡
But I won't give up on scoring
a goal until the very end.
That's the sort of person a striker is.
それが ｽﾄﾗｲｶｰって生き物だ｡
残り時間で
ｵﾚ１人ででもｺﾞｰﾙを決める｡
During the time that's left, I'll score
a goal even if I have to do it alone.
息子が ｺﾞｰﾙを待ってる｡
My little boy...is waiting for a goal.
だがｱﾝﾀ 腰も膝も
もうﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛなんだろ？
But isn't your back and knees a wreck?
ﾌｯ 素人のお前たちに
何か期待するよりﾏｼだ｡
They give me more of a chance
than relying on you amateurs.
やってみてわかったろ｡
You realize it now, don't you?
Soccer is not a game.
ｻｯｶｰは遊びじゃねえ！
The field is a battleground.
Soccer is war!
ﾋﾟｯﾁは戦場だ｡ ｻｯｶｰは戦争なんだ！
《みんな:えっ 戦争？》
War?!
ﾌﾌｯ ﾌﾌﾌﾌｯ…｡
What's so funny?!
何がおかしい？
甘羅尾さん ｱﾝﾀも人が悪いや｡
Amarao-san, you son-of-a-gun.
確かにここにいる
連中は ｻｯｶｰは素人だ｡
All of us here are definitely
amateurs at soccer.
だがなぁ
戦争ってなりゃ 話は別だ｡
But, if it's war, we're talking about...
ｺｲﾂら全員 一騎当千の玄人揃いだ｡
Everyone here is a battle-hardened pro.
Huh?
はぁ？
まぁ 見てろ｡
Just watch.
≪さぁ 残る時間は
ﾛｽﾀｲﾑのみとなりました｡
All that remains is stoppage time.
勝敗が決まってしまった今➡
With the outcome already decided,
the only question is whether or not Amarao
will score a goal in his retirement match.
注目は 甘羅尾が 引退試合を➡
自らのｺﾞｰﾙで
飾れるかどうかというところです｡
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
≪甘羅尾 また単独で切れ込む！
Amarao speeds in alone once again!
Tsk! That pain again...
《ｸｯ また痛みが…》
The ball is taken away!
≪あぁっと ﾎﾞｰﾙが奪われた！
And it goes back...
そして そのﾎﾞｰﾙは 前線に！
the other way!
ﾏｽﾞｲ！
戻るな！
Crap!
Don't come here!
ｱﾝﾀは ｺﾞｰﾙだけを狙ってろ！
You go for a goal, nothing else!
お膳立ては ｵﾚたちがしてやる！
We'll set you up!
うお～っ！
これ以上取らせるかぁ～っ！
You're not scoring any more points!
Fools! Amateurs shouldn't rush in!
ﾊﾞｶ 素人が
不用意に突っ込むんじゃねえ！
You're wrong! He's not just any amateur!
違う ｱｲﾂはただの素人じゃねえ！
あっ あれは？
うお～っ！
He's...
(甘羅尾)あれは足軽！
Is that?! A foot soldier?!
One who rushes in with
no fear for his life?!
命を失うことを恐れず
突進する足軽なのかっ？
I'm used to diving in and
sacrificing myself!
こちとら 命を捨てる
ﾀﾞｲﾋﾞﾝｸﾞくらい 慣れっこなんだよ！
うっ！
ええ～っ！
くっ やはり足軽じゃ…｡
よく見ろ！
He's just a foot soldier, after all.
Look closely!
あっ！
(桂)うお～っ！
The foot solder was a decoy!
足軽はｵﾄﾘ！
その後ろの長槍隊が本命だっ｡
The real defenders are the
spearmen behind him!
(桂)どりゃ～っ！
行きますよ お妙さん！
Let's do it, Otae-san!
(甘羅尾)おおっ！
上空の獲物を狙う➡
That figure going after the ball
in mid-air has to be an archer!
あの姿は まさしく弓矢隊！
(近藤)いくぞ ｽｶｲﾗﾌﾞｺﾞﾘｹｰﾝ！
(お妙)ﾊｯ！
Go! Sky Love Gorricane!
[Note: Parody of "Sky love Hurricane", special attack
by the Tachibana Brothers in Captain Tsubasa.]
Look out! There's a defender
in the path of the pass!
(甘羅尾)ﾏｽﾞｲ ﾊﾟｽｺｰｽに相手が！
This one's mine!
ﾍｯ いただきだぜ！
Do you know...
あなた 戦場において➡
who the fastest person on
a battlefield is?
誰がいちばん速いか知らないの？
It's...
それは… 忍びよ！
the shinobi!
おっ！ 新八 ﾜﾝﾂｰﾊﾟｽでいくｱﾙ｡
Shinpachi! Let's do this with a
back-and-forth pass attack.
Right.
おう！
ﾎｲ ﾊﾟｽ！
Here's the pass!
Pass.
ﾊﾟｽ！
What a combination!
なんて ｺﾝﾋﾞﾈｰｼｮﾝだ！
It's the Takeda Cavalry! The strongest
during wartime Japan!
あれは まさに
戦国最強 武田騎馬隊！
What?! I'm a horse?!
あれ？ ﾎﾞｸ馬！
お前ら 何やってんだ！
What're you guys doing?!
There's only Amarao left! Defend him!
最後は
甘羅尾しかねえんだ ﾏｰｸしろ！
うお～っ！
《なに？》
What?!
Samurai-san, leave this guy
to me and go on ahead.
お侍さん
ここはﾜｼに任せて 先に…｡
みんなのためにｺﾞｰﾙを…｡
Score a goal for everyone.
(甘羅尾)お～い
かっこよすぎるだろ ｱﾝﾀ！
Hey! You're way too cool!
銀ちゃん！
うお～っ！
Gin-chan!
Go, Amarao!
いくぞ 甘羅尾 決めろ！
Score!
[Go!]
For the sake of your little boy!
ﾃﾒｴの 息子のために！
うお～っ！
《ありがとうみんな そして…》
Thank you, everyone...
And...!
Amarao!
甘羅尾！
《甘羅尾:お華ちゃ～ん！》
Ohana-chan!
What?!
(みんな)えっ？
(甘羅尾)ｵﾚの息子のために➡
Go out with me for the
sake of my "little boy"!
つき合ってください ｼｭｰﾄ！
Shoot!
うわ～っ！
お お… 折れた｡
I-It...snapped...
(ﾎｲｯｽﾙ)
≪ここで試合終了です｡
And that's the end of the game!
C'mon, let's go home.
おい 帰るぞ｡
父ちゃん！
Daddy!
ﾍﾟｯ｡
《ｽﾄﾗｲｶｰ｡ それは ｺﾞｰﾙという
獲物を追い続ける 獣…》
Strikers are beasts that
live to score goals.
The next episode... "Kids Don't Understand
How Their Parents Feel."
[The Odd Jobs are summoned to a splendid mansion owned
by their client Kaguzo Mashiroi, boss of the Mashiroi Gang.]
[His son, Utsuzo, had become reclusive. Can
Gin-san and friends coax him out of his shell?]